When an incident hits,
Dynatrace alerts the SRE team and takes
them straight to the problem.
Instead of scrambling to figure out what
broke and where,
Dynatrace provides a direct link to the
Problems app.
One click and you're in Dynatrace.
It has already detected the issue and
correlated all telemetry signals.
So the incident overview tells you
exactly what Front End app is affected,
how many services are involved,
and how many users are impacted.
And it gets better.
Harnessing the power of Dynatrace
intelligence,
Assist explains the incident,
why it happened, and how to remediate it.
The context is enriched through your
preferred CICD tooling,
in this case Argo CD and Assist directs
you to the PR and the exact file that
caused the incident.
No more hunting through your Git history.
When you expand the code,
you can see exactly where things went
wrong.
In this case,
we can see that one of the credit card
brands is not being accepted.
The culprit was just a variable change,
but in a more complex problem spanning
over multiple files,
we could simply revert the PR and then
look for the root cause.
Now we're in the Services app
investigating the problem.
We will select the Properties tab to
understand which team owns the service
that has failed.
As you can see,
we would want to notify someone from Team
Financial Services regarding the failure.
No lengthy internal investigation to find
the responsible team.
Normally your investigation would end
here,
but let's imagine we're in the role of
the owning team conducting A deeper
analysis.
Specify the time frame when the error hit.
Now you've zeroed in on the key signals.
Select a particular failure marked in red.
Here we can see where the error occurred
in the trace.
Select the Exceptions tab to see the
exact line of code where the exception
was thrown.
Now for a front end problem,
it's important to know what the user
actually saw when experiencing this
payment issue.
From the incident overview.
Let's analyse the error in the Error
Inspector app.
In Error Inspector,
in the context of our problem,
we click Analyse, select the exception,
first party error,
click on the session ID to understand
what the user saw when this payment issue
occurred.
Scrub through the clip to see every click
and every screen prior to failure.
The red markings in the timeline will
tell you exactly when the error occurred.
In this case,
the UI did not provide the user any
visual feedback.
This completes our investigation.
The error was traced from the back end to
the front end.
The responsible team was informed and the
root cause was determined.
Start your Dynatrace trial today.